toonpool.com 2019-11-04

# Privacy | Cartoons, Caricatures, Cartoon Images | TOONPOOL

## Your privacy is important to **toonpool.com**.

### This privacy policy describes the kinds of information we collect, how we collect it, and how we use it.

## Privacy Policy

### toonpool.com

### Privacy Policy

for customers, prospects and visitors of our website 

We collect, process and use your personal data exclusively in compliance with the applicable data protection regulations. 

With the following information, we would like to give you an overview of the processing of your personal data by us and your rights under the Data Protection Act. Which data is processed in detail and how it is used depends largely on the services used or agreed upon. Therefore, not all parts of this information will apply to you. This privacy policy explains how toonpool.com ("toonpool", "Toon Agent" ® "we", "us" or "our") collects, uses and shares your information. 

Where applicable, you consent to the use of your data as described in this privacy statement as soon as you use our services, which is why we ask that you read this document carefully and contact usif you have questions. 

Responsible authority in the sense of the data protection laws, in particular the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), is:   
toonpool.com GmbH  
c / o Max Pohlenz  
Blumenthalstr. 3-4  
10783 Berlin, Germany 

### Your Affected Rights

You can always exercise the following rights under the contact details of our data protection officer: 

  * Information about your stored data and their processing, 
  * Correction of incorrect personal data, 
  * Deletion of your data stored with us, 
  * Restriction of data processing, if we are not yet allowed to delete your data due to legal obligations, 
  * Objection to the processing of your data with us and 
  * Data portability, if you have consented to the data processing or have signed a contract with us. 

If you have given us your consent, you can withdraw it at any time with effect for the future. You can always contact the supervisory authority responsible for you with a complaint. Your competent supervisory authority will depend on the state of your domicile, work or alleged violation. A list of the supervisory authorities (for the non-public area) with address can be found under: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>. 

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

Personal data is information that identifies you directly or indirectly. Personal information also includes anonymous data associated with information that identifies you, directly or indirectly. Personal information does not include data that has been irreversibly anonymized, so that we no longer have the ability, whether by other means or otherwise, to identify you. 

Below are descriptions of the types of personal information we collect from you and how we use it: 

### Collecting general information when visiting our website

When you access our website, a cookie automatically saves information of a general nature. This information (server log files) includes, for example, the type of web browser, the operating system used, the domain name of your Internet service provider and the like. This is the only information that does not allow conclusions about your person. This information is technically necessary to correctly deliver the contents of web pages requested by you and is mandatory when using the internet. They are processed in particular for the following purposes: 

  * Ensure a stable connection to the site,
  * Ensuring a smooth use of our website,
  * Evaluation of system security and stability as well as
  * for further administrative purposes.

The processing of your personal data is based on our legitimate interest for the aforementioned purposes of data collection. We do not use your information to draw conclusions about you. The recipient of the data is only the responsible body and possibly the processor. 

Anonymous information of this kind may be statistically evaluated by us to optimize our website and the underlying technology. 

### Cookies

Like many other websites, we also use so-called "cookies". Cookies are small text files that are transferred from a website server to your hard drive. This automatically gives us certain data, such as IP address, browser used, operating system and your connection to the Internet. 

Cookies can not be used to launch programs or to transfer viruses to a computer. Based on the information contained in cookies, we can facilitate navigation and enable the correct display of our websites. In no case will the data collected by us be passed on to third parties or a link with personal data will be established without your consent. 

Of course, you can also view our website without cookies. Internet browsers are regularly set to accept cookies. In general, you can disable the use of cookies at any time through the settings of your browser. Please use the help features of your internet browser to find out how to change these settings. Please note that some features of our website may not work if you have disabled the use of cookies. 

### Registration on our website

When registering for the use of our personalized services, some personal information will be collected, such as name, address, contact and communication information such as telephone number and e-mail address. If you are registered with us, you can access content and services that we offer only to registered users. Registered users also have the option of changing or deleting the data specified during registration at any time. Of course, we also provide you with information about the personal data we hold about you at any time. We are happy to rectify or delete these at your request, as far as no statutory storage requirements preclude. To contact us in this context, please use the contact details given at the end of this Privacy Policy. 

### Comment function

When users leave comments on our site, they will also be saved the time of their creation and the username previously chosen by the site visitor. This is for our security, as we may be prosecuted for any illegal content on our website, even if created by users. 

### Newsletter

On the basis of your expressly given consent, we will regularly send you our newsletter or comparable information by e-mail to your specified e-mail address. 

For the receipt of the newsletter the indication of your E-Mail address is sufficient. When you sign up to receive our newsletter, the data you provide will be used exclusively for this purpose. Subscribers may also be notified by email about circumstances relevant to the service or registration (such as changes to the newsletter offer or technical conditions). 

For an effective registration we need a valid e-mail address. In order to verify that an application is actually made by the owner of an e-mail address, we use the "Double opt-in" procedure. For this purpose we record the order of the newsletter, the dispatch of a confirmation mail and the receipt of the requested answer. Further data is not collected. The data will be used exclusively for the newsletter and will not be passed on to third parties. 

The consent to the storage of your personal data and their use for the newsletter can be revoked at any time. Each newsletter has a link to it. In addition, you can unsubscribe from this website at any time or inform us of your request via the contact option indicated at the end of this Privacy Notice. 

### Contact forms

If you have questions of any kind contact us by e-mail or contact form, you give us your consent for the purpose of contacting you. This requires the specification of a valid e-mail address. This serves for the assignment of the request and the subsequent answering of the same. The specification of further data is optional. The information you provide will be stored for the purpose of processing the request and for possible follow-up questions. After completion of the request and expiration of any legal deadlines, personal data will be automatically deleted. 

### SSL encryption

To protect the security of your data during transmission, we use state-of-the-art encryption techniques (such as SSL) via HTTPS protocol. 

### Hyperlinks, links to third party websites

We give our members of the community the opportunity to link to their other offers via weblink. Therefore, there are so-called hyperlinks to websites of other providers on our website, which you can follow by clicking on them. In these cases, they will be redirected from our website directly to the other providers' website. You recognize this when the URL changes. Because we have an international offer, these sites may also be hosted outside the EU (e.g. in the US) where other privacy policies than GDPR may apply. We do not forward any data to the external website when the page is changed. 

If you have been forwarded to the website of a member or other platform via hyperlink, the use of your data is subject to the privacy regulations of this company and the respective country. We can not take responsibility for the confidentiality of your personal information as we have no control over compliance with European data protection legislation. We are not responsible for the privacy practices used by such third party vendors or the information or content contained in their products and services. If you have any uncertainties, please contact the external website operator directly or the member who provides this link. This Privacy Policy applies only to data collected by us. We encourage you to read the third-party privacy policies before using their websites, products, or services. 

### Purposes of data processing by the responsible authority and third parties

We process personal data that we receive from our customers or users as part of our business relationship. In addition, we process - insofar as necessary for the provision of our services - personal data that we legitimately gain from publicly available sources (such as trade and association registers, press, internet) or that are transmitted to us by other third parties. 

We process your personal data only for the purposes stated in this privacy policy. A transfer of your personal data to third parties for purposes other than those mentioned does not take place. We only share your personal information with third parties if: 

  * You have given your explicit consent,
  * processing is required to complete a contract with you,
  * processing is required to fulfill a legal obligation
  * processing is necessary to protect legitimate interests and there is no reason to believe that you have an overriding legitimate interest in not disclosing your information.

We process personal data in accordance with the provisions of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) 

**a. for the fulfillment of contractual obligations (Article 6 paragraph 1b GDPR)**  
The processing takes place in the context of the execution of our contracts with our customers and suppliers (artists) or for the execution of pre-contractual measures, on request by mail, telephone or post office, after registration with the Toon Agent® (customers) or in the community portal toonpool.com (Suppliers). 

**b. in the context of the balancing of interests (Article 6 paragraph 1f of the GDPR)**  
If necessary, we process your data beyond the actual fulfillment of the contract to safeguard certain interests of us or third parties. Examples: 

  * Ensuring IT security and IT operation of our web site, 
  * Prevention and investigation of criminal offenses, 
  * Asserting legal claims and defense in legal disputes, 
  * Consultation and exchange of data with credit bureaus (e.g., SCHUFA, creditreform) to identify credit risk in business dealings, 
  * Review and optimization of requirements analysis procedures for direct customer approach, 
  * Advertising or market research, provided that you have not objected to the use of your data. 
  * Measures for the further development of services and products 

**c. based on your consent (Article 6 paragraph 1a of the GDPR)**  
Insofar as you have given us consent to the processing of personal data for specific purposes (e.g. "Daily Toon" newsletter, registration in the Community Portal, registration in the Toon Agent®), the legality of this processing is based on your consent. A given consent can be revoked at any time. This also applies to the revocation of declarations of consent, which were declared to us before the validity of the GDPR, i.e. before May 25, 2018. The revocation of consent is only effective for the future and does not affect the legality of the data processed until the revocation. 

**d. due to legal requirements (article 6 paragraph 1c GDPR) or in the public interest (article 6 paragraph 1e of the GDPR)**  
We process and store your personal data as long as this is necessary for the fulfillment of our contractual and legal obligations. If the data are no longer required for the fulfillment of contractual or legal obligations, these are regularly deleted, unless their temporary processing is necessary for the following purposes: 

  * Fulfillment of commercial and tax-related retention requirements, e.g. from the German Commercial Code (HGB). The specified retention periods are usually up to 10 years. 
  * Preservation of evidence in the context of the statutory statute of limitations (§195 German Civil Code) 

As part of a business relationship with us, you must provide the personal information that is required to initiate, conduct, and terminate a business relationship and to fulfill its contractual obligations or that we are required to collect. Without this data, we will generally be unable to conclude, execute and terminate a contract with you. 

### e-mail traffic

Any e-mail traffic, necessary for registration on toonpool.com and the ToonAgent®, for newsletters "Daily Toon", community-internal mailings, etc., takes place via a provider abroad (USA). This provider operates according to the rules of the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework, which according to the adequacy decision of the EU Commission acc. Article 45 (3) GDPR provides an adequate level of data protection. We monitor this processing on a regular basis and may take action if the privacy policy changes. e-mails and mailings are transmitted via encrypted data transmission (SSL). 

### Using Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (following: Google). Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", i.e. text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, due to the activation of IP anonymization on these websites, your IP address will be shortened beforehand by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. 

The purposes of the data processing are the evaluation of the use of the website and the compilation of reports on activities on the website. Based on the use of the website and the Internet, other related services will be provided. The processing is based on the legitimate interest of the website operator. 

You can prevent the storage of cookies by a corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. In addition, you may prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading the browser plug-in available under the following link and install: [Browser Add-on to disable Google Analytics ](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). 

In addition or as an alternative to the browser add-on, you can prevent tracking by Google Analytics on our pages by clicking this link. An opt-out cookie will be installed on your device. This will prevent the collection by Google Analytics for this website and for this browser in the future, as long as the cookie remains installed in your browser. 

### Google AdSense

1\. Our website uses Google AdSense, an online advertising service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google AdSense uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on the user's computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website. Google AdSense also uses so-called web beacons (invisible graphics). These web beacons can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this offer. The information generated by cookies and web beacons about the use of this website (including the IP address of the users) and the delivery of advertising formats are transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. This information may be shared by Google with Google affiliates. However, Google will not merge your IP address with other data you have stored. 

2\. Users can prevent the installation of Google AdSense cookies in various ways:   
a) by setting the browser software accordingly;   
b) by disabling interest-based ads on Google;   
c) by deactivating the interest-based ads of the providers that are part of the "About Ads" self-regulatory campaign;   
d) by permanent deactivation by a browser plug-in. 

The settings under b) and c) are deleted when cookies are deleted in the browser settings. 3\. Further information on privacy and cookies for advertising on Google AdSense can be found in the Google Privacy Policy, in particular the following links: [http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) [http://www.google.com/intl/en/ policies/technologies/ads](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/technologies/ads) [http://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090)  

### Your rights

We take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete and up-to-date. You have a right to information, rectification and cancellation regarding the personal data collected by us. In addition, you are entitled to object or restrict the further processing of your personal data at any time. You are entitled to receive your personal data in a structured and common format. Regarding the processing of your personal data, you can file a complaint against the relevant data protection authority. 

In order to ensure the protection and security of your personal information, we may request information from you so that we can confirm your identity and your right of access to this information, and we can also search for and provide you with the personal information we hold about you. In some cases, it may enable us to comply with applicable laws or regulatory requirements, or we may be required to refuse or delete any or all of our personal information. 

If you wish to exercise your rights, please use our contact form. We will answer your request within a reasonable time frame, but in any case in less than 7 days. 

### Children

We do not consciously collect, use or disclose information from children under the age of 16. If we are aware that we have collected the personal information of a child under the age of 16, we will take steps to erase the information as soon as possible. Please contact us immediately if a child under the age of 16 has provided us with personal data. 

### Change to our privacy policy

We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy to always comply with the latest legal requirements or to implement changes to our services in the privacy policy, e.g. when introducing new services. Any future privacy policies would be applicable to your future visit. 

### Questions to the Data Protection Officer

If you have any privacy concerns, please email us or contact the person responsible for privacy in our organization:   
Contact for all privacy issues: Max Pohlenz 

This privacy policy has been compiled in part with the [activeMind AG Privacy Policy Generator ](https://www.activemind.de/datenschutz/datenschutzhinweis-generator/). The Google AdSense notice is from the intersoft consulting services AG .
